<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jeffrey Frith</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Visual artist</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 11:58:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.12</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">117361521</site>	<item>
		<title>Artist&#8217;s Books</title>
		<link>/artists-books/</link>
		<comments>/artists-books/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 05:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=801</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Artist’s books As yet there is no clear definition of what constitutes an artist’s book. Good, artists can keep exploring the boundaries of this genre. Looking at a small collection of Artist’s books held by the National Gallery of Australia I was struck by the different ways the artists had gone about producing their book. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/artists-books/">Artist&#8217;s Books</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-624 size-large" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_0770-768x1024-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_0770-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_0770-768x1024-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/09/IMG_0770-768x1024-400x533.jpg 400w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
<h2>Artist’s books</h2>
<p>As yet there is no clear definition of what constitutes an artist’s book. Good, artists can keep exploring the boundaries of this genre.</p>
<p>Looking at a small collection of Artist’s books held by the National Gallery of Australia I was struck by the different ways the artists had gone about producing their book. Some were A3 size and were stapled or bound so that they looked like books or loose pages placed in a shallow box. Some limited to an edition of six, others in an edition of a hundred.</p>
<p><strong>History</strong><br />
There is a history of artists making books spanning hundreds of years. What is it about books made by artists that link them together? It is the ability of the artist to have full control over the way the book is created and looks, independent of publishers.</p>
<p>Today new technology, new ideas, and new ways of connecting through social media enhance how these books are produced and distributed. I recently published a book, Between the lines, a small anthology of Haiku inspired verse together with a number of my life drawings. The book is available in limited edition print format or electronically.</p>
<p><strong>Printmakers</strong><br />
Printmakers have often been drawn to produce multiple artist’s books as they have access to multiple copies of their original prints. I recently experimented by cutting up one of my lithographic prints to use in a small hand-made ‘concertina’ book, Dark Matters.</p>
<p>As the book is opened each panel features part of the print accompanied by text.<br />
The book takes the reader on a journey through time and space referring as it does to Stephen Hawking and Black holes and to poets and musicians who have different feelings to express.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/artists-books/">Artist&#8217;s Books</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/artists-books/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">801</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connecting with people and places</title>
		<link>/tangle-of-torsos/</link>
		<comments>/tangle-of-torsos/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 05:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=795</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I travelled half way around the world recently to reconnect with friends on the island known as Martha’s Vineyard south of Cape Cod Massachusetts. I was amazed to learn that there is no Martha and there is no vineyard. How could this be? There is one theory indicating at one time native wild grape vines [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tangle-of-torsos/">Connecting with people and places</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I travelled half way around the world recently to reconnect with friends on the island known as Martha’s Vineyard south of Cape Cod Massachusetts. I was amazed to learn that there is no Martha and there is no vineyard. How could this be? There is one theory indicating at one time native wild grape vines covered the island. One of the earliest settlers was called Martin so it’s possible that over time Martin’s vineyard morphed into Martha’s Vineyard.</p>
<p>My friends fell in love with the island some thirty years ago and built a holiday house on an idyllic for their family spot. They followed the local tradition of building post and beam structures clad in clapboard siding and shingles. The structures relate beautifully with the muted colours of the surrounding seaside landscape.</p>
<p>Knowing my keen interest in art my host booked me a place with his life-drawing group. Great idea. I appreciated the opportunity of linking up with some of the other local artists.</p>
<p>My supply of paper is limited. I must accommodate numerous figures on a page instead of drawing just one figure. The model disrobes there in front of me, naked, moving easily to strike a pose. Self assured moving from one two-minute pose to the next.</p>
<p>It’s all about balance and dynamic tension, subtle shifts of weight, realignment of the shoulders, a turn of the head and a twist of the torso. Reclining on cushions for a longer pose the body takes on a languid air. Good lighting creates highlights, shadows and drama.</p>
<p>I move my charcoal rapidly over the page each image having sufficient detail to catch the eye. One sketch finishes another starts images flow into each other. My mind free from distraction senses the sculptural qualities of the figure before me.</p>
<p>Capturing the essence of the pose extends my observational skills as well as eye/hand co-ordination. The many figures on the paper become a tangle of torsos imbued with feeling.</p>
<p>The model is a mature woman lots of curves and I go with the delightful flow of her body. Models are often the best timekeepers. Knowing when to move to a different pose is a skill in itself.</p>
<p>Short poses a really warm- up exercises just to get your eye in. Longer poses make physical demands on the model to keep still being relaxed but not so relaxed that sleep beckons.</p>
<p>Standing by my easel at the back of the room I am aware of others in the group bent over their drawing boards presenting me with a picture of intense concentration.</p>
<p>Time passes quickly. The session ends with the model donning her dressing gown. She makes a quick tour of the room looking at her image as seen through many pairs of eyes. I wonder what is going through her mind as she peruses the work. Does she have a favourite one? Of course, if she doesn’t find one she likes, she may well think, “why did I bother!”</p>
<p>I too am interested to see what others have done, what medium they used to draw, what feelings they captured. While I pack up my gear the person in front of me looked up from her desk at my drawings. “You have captured her alright. I like the way you use the pencil.”</p>
<p>A discussion ensued. We were able to talk about each other’s technique, she uses a lead pencil while I use charcoal. Her drawings are of the complete figure small yet detailed, my drawings focus on parts of the figure significant to the pose rendered in strong flowing lines.</p>
<p>On the way home I chatted with my friend and learnt that he had kept folios of his work over the past few years. Keeping drawings enables critical analysis to discover what works well and what can be improved.</p>
<p>There is nothing quite like the practice of drawing with a live model. Although the time is short a relationship builds between artist and model, few words are spoken. For the brief time spent together both artist and model in different fashion bare their souls.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-800 alignleft" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2043-225x300.jpeg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2043-225x300.jpeg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2043.jpeg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /> <img class="size-medium wp-image-798 alignleft" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2044-225x300.jpeg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2044-225x300.jpeg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2044.jpeg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /> <img class="size-medium wp-image-799 alignleft" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2045-300x225.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2045-300x225.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2045.jpeg 320w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div id="attachment_797" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="size-medium wp-image-797" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2042-225x300.jpeg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2042-225x300.jpeg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/09/IMG_2042.jpeg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The moving figure captured in the moment.</p></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/tangle-of-torsos/">Connecting with people and places</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/tangle-of-torsos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">795</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PIRATE PARTY -THE BOOK</title>
		<link>/pirate-party-book/</link>
		<comments>/pirate-party-book/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=787</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Pirate Party You may wonder why I chose to create a children&#8217;s book. The answer is simple really; I have a grandson. What better gift than to create a book where I do the story and all the illustrations. Where to start My parents gave me a pirate party when I was a youngster. Such [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pirate-party-book/">PIRATE PARTY -THE BOOK</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-792" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629.jpg" alt="" width="3024" height="4032" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629.jpg 3024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629-400x533.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1629-800x1067.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-790" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1.jpg" alt="" width="2975" height="4032" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1.jpg 2975w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1-221x300.jpg 221w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1-768x1041.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1-756x1024.jpg 756w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1-400x542.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1785-1-800x1084.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 2975px) 100vw, 2975px" /><strong>Pirate Party</strong><br />
You may wonder why I chose to create a children&#8217;s book. The answer is simple really; I have a grandson. What better gift than to create a book where I do the story and all the illustrations.</p>
<p><strong>Where to start</strong><br />
My parents gave me a pirate party when I was a youngster. Such fun as I dressed as a pirate and all my mates did too! And that was just the beginning. Dad thought a good place to hold the party was underneath the house. There was head room for little people but grown-ups would have to lean over so as not to bump their heads.</p>
<p><strong>What to do</strong><br />
Imagine you are under the house where it is dark even during the day. A bit scary but a real sense of adventure as we looked for a map. The map would lead us to the treasure chest.</p>
<p><strong>Finding treasure</strong><br />
Searching everywhere for the treasure we did not have to fight each other with our cardboard swords. Perhaps that was just as well. Eventually we found the treasure chest and guess what we found inside? The best kind of treasure, stuff you could eat; chocolate frogs, silver balls and many good things.</p>
<p><strong>Party time</strong><br />
What was that. We heard a noise. We were being called, &#8220;Come and get it&#8221;. We stumbled over each other into the bright daylight and gathered around a table set up in the garden. Lots of food and of course a big birthday cake. What a great day.</p>
<p><strong>Writing the story</strong><br />
I decided to write in verse as it came easily and sounded good when read aloud. For those listening to the story verse is easy to remember because of the rhythm and rhyme.</p>
<p><strong>Torn paper illustrations</strong><br />
To keep in the party mood I decide the images would not be too formal but required some imagination to work out what was going on. I created images using tissue paper. Some detail I drew with a brush and ink and highlighted with a silver ink pen. Loads of fun.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/pirate-party-book/">PIRATE PARTY -THE BOOK</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/pirate-party-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">787</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Showing Sculpture</title>
		<link>/showing-sculpture/</link>
		<comments>/showing-sculpture/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 05:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=782</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Displaying sculpture How best to display sculpture,once it leaves your studio is always an issue. For large works Henry Moore said, &#8220;Sculpture is an art of the open air. Daylight, sunlight, is necessary to it, and for me, setting and complement is nature.&#8221; I have achieved what Moore had in mind with my granite sculpture [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/showing-sculpture/">Showing Sculpture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_784" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" class="size-full wp-image-784" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774.jpg 4032w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774-400x300.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1774-800x600.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">EYE OF THE STORM</p></div>
<p><div id="attachment_785" style="width: 3034px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776.jpg" alt="" width="3024" height="4032" class="size-full wp-image-785" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776.jpg 3024w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776-400x533.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/IMG_1776-800x1067.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 3024px) 100vw, 3024px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">EYE OF THE STORM</p></div>Displaying sculpture</p>
<p>How best to display sculpture,once it leaves your studio is always an issue. For large works Henry Moore said, &#8220;Sculpture is an art of the open air. Daylight, sunlight, is necessary to it, and for me, setting and complement is nature.&#8221;</p>
<p>I have achieved what Moore had in mind with my granite sculpture BALANCE now displayed in an outdoor setting at my old school, Camberwell Grammar, Melbourne. It sits well in the designed outdoor space and complements it too.</p>
<p>Garden settings</p>
<p>This year I return to the Willowtree Sculpture Park, Laggan, NSW for another show which takes place in early November 2017. It is a bonus to have a curator assist with the siting of the sculptures in the 150 year old garden. Works could potentially be lost amongst the huge Pine trees.</p>
<p>Does it feel right</p>
<p>Unlike paintings done on a 2 dimensional surface sculpture working with 3 dimensions takes up space and space has an energy component. Think of personal space. We don&#8217;t like it if someone we are talking to comes too close which can be seen as invading our personal space. Similarly sculptures need to be in just the right spot so people can view it from all sides without tripping over the work!</p>
<p>Security</p>
<p>Is the work safe? Is it liable to fall on someone? Can people safely touch the work? One of my 1.2 metre high stone sculptures was destined to be placed in a public space at a correctional centre courtyard area. The wardens object to the work on the grounds that the sculpture had a hole right through the stone. They argued that it might be possible someone would put their arm in the hole and might break their arm trying to remove it.</p>
<p>Display stand</p>
<p>Medium to small stone sculpture usually need to be displayed on a plinth  or a stand of some sort. But what is to stop the work from toppling off the stand or being removed without authorisation? I have developed a metal bracket for my sculpture EYE OF THE STORM which secures the stone sculpture with screws at the back of the work.</p>
<p>Museum displays</p>
<p>Museum curators face many issues dealing with safety and security. Museums and large galleries are good places to see how the professionals do it. Purpose made metal brackets are used extensively and clear perspex used where the metal might be distracting.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/showing-sculpture/">Showing Sculpture</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/showing-sculpture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">782</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Framing print focus</title>
		<link>/framing-print-focus/</link>
		<comments>/framing-print-focus/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 02:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; Focus on framing I recently framed a lithographic print COMING HOME I made a couple of years ago. I have looked at the image many times and thought it lacked focus. But now the picture is framed I see it with &#8216;new eyes&#8217;. All the lines are resolved. Focus Of course the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/framing-print-focus/">Framing print focus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_777" style="width: 4042px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="size-full wp-image-777" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866.jpg 4032w, /wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866-400x300.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2011/06/IMG_1866-800x600.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 4032px) 100vw, 4032px" /><p class="wp-caption-text">COMING HOME</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Focus on framing<br />
I recently framed a lithographic print COMING HOME I made a couple of years ago. I have looked at the image many times and thought it lacked focus. But now the picture is framed I see it with &#8216;new eyes&#8217;. All the lines are resolved.</h3>
<p><strong>Focus</strong><br />
Of course the main function of the frame is to focus attention by creating a visual boundary. The frame I had was white and I felt it did little to create the visual boundary I had in mind. So I sprayed the frame a dull black. What a difference the colour made.</p>
<p><strong>Matt</strong><br />
The matt is also important . It provides space for the image so it can &#8216;breathe&#8217;. Matts come in all colours and even textures. This image is printed in black ink and is fairly dark in appearance. I chose a matt with a muted warm colour to emphasise the white paper on which the image is printed.</p>
<p><strong>Protection</strong><br />
The print has a stiff composite board as a backing and the front is glass. Polishing the glass both sides ensures no finger marks will be left. The glass does not press against the print but is supported on the matt. The glass protects the print from accidental damage while being handled and from dust.</p>
<p><strong>Framing without glass</strong><br />
I have a large print I purchased from a fellow artist. The work is framed with recycled timber and has a generous antique white matt. However, the artist did not use glass to protect the work. He felt the glossy surface of the glass would detract from the beautiful rich blacks he had achieved on the print.</p>
<p><strong>Alternatives</strong><br />
Large works need a big frame and a big piece of glass. The glass is quite heavy and expensive and easily broken. I have used a non-reflective clear plastic panel with some success. Not only does the panel protect the art work it does not have a glossy appearance. On occasions reflections on the surface of polished glass can be quite distracting and detract from the art work.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/framing-print-focus/">Framing print focus</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/framing-print-focus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">776</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Imagery as insight</title>
		<link>/imagery-as-insight/</link>
		<comments>/imagery-as-insight/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 04:56:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=765</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Drawing is the universal language. I am sure my dad was not the first person to say it but it was he who passed on this gem to me. And my experience has born out the truth of this statement. Time travel Travelling to many parts of the world and have witnessed how the simple [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/imagery-as-insight/">Imagery as insight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Drawing is the universal language.</p>
<p>I am sure my dad was not the first person to say it but it was he who passed on this gem to me. And my experience has born out the truth of this statement.</p>
<p>Time travel</p>
<p>Travelling to many parts of the world and have witnessed how the simple act of drawing attracts a crowd. Whether in the highland villages of New Guinea, the market places in Morocco or in Taronga Park zoo in Sydney people just love to see an artist at work. In many cases words are not spoken; who needs words when greeted with big smiles.</p>
<p>Illustrations</p>
<p>I enjoy illustrating stories and poems by others. While living in London I had the opportunity to illustrate works by Somerset Maughan ; Liza of Lambeth and On a Chinese screen. Researching the period in which the tales were set, the architecture, the people and their clothes, the landscape, was part of the pleasure of doing the drawings.</p>
<p>Body of work</p>
<p>When asked to illustrate a body of work from a gifted writer and performance poet I made a decision upfront. Rather than attempting to illustrate individual poems I will tackle the underlying elements, water, earth, fire and air that link all of the poems.</p>
<p>Style</p>
<p>Each tool I use be it a pencil, charcoal stick, pen or brush and ink has distinct qualities that dictate the style of the drawing. For this latest project FULLmoonshakes by Stuart Boag I am using a stick of compressed charcoal. By using the stick on its side the marks I make have a calligraphic quality. I like the fluid lines sharp edges and almost 3D quality of the mainly abstract forms I draw.</p>
<p>Colour</p>
<p>Kimono is another of Stuart Boag’s projects which ‘celebrates beauty and wonder’ in parable and verse. This work inspired by Japanese kiminos Stuart collected over many years called for the use of colour in the illustrations. I use torn strips of coloured tissue paper to provide a fragile texture as well as colour. I use a Japanese brush and black ink for detail; a strong combination.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-764 size-large aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IMG_1022-768x1024.jpg" alt="img_1022" width="768" height="1024" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IMG_1022-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IMG_1022-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IMG_1022-400x533.jpg 400w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/12/IMG_1022-800x1067.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/imagery-as-insight/">Imagery as insight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/imagery-as-insight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">765</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Willowtree sculpture garden</title>
		<link>/willowtree-sculpture-garden/</link>
		<comments>/willowtree-sculpture-garden/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=758</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A magic garden What a wonderful rambling garden with some trees over 150 years old. It seems Henry Moore was right, sculpture is best seen in a natural setting. . So this exhibition at Willowtree sculpture garden is part of a 9 open gardens festival at Laggan, NSW.  I enjoyed the opening ceremony and the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/willowtree-sculpture-garden/">Willowtree sculpture garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A magic garden</strong></p>
<p>What a wonderful rambling garden with some trees over 150 years old. It seems Henry Moore was right, sculpture is best seen in a natural setting. . So this exhibition at Willowtree sculpture garden is part of a 9 open gardens festival at Laggan, NSW.  I enjoyed the opening ceremony and the haunting sounds of didgeridoo and guitar.</p>
<p><b>The exhibition</b></p>
<p>Artists have their work on display for the month of November 2016. Many of the works are carved in stone or wood or fabricated and cast in metal and ceramic. Abstract works carved in Shona stone seem popular. The black stone carves well takes a high polish and has great visual appeal.</p>
<p><strong>My work &#8216;Mindstream&#8217; </strong></p>
<p>Carving a sandstone rock sourced from a coastal area in NSW south coast is great fun. Each stone has a story and I do my best to let the stone speak. It comes as no surprise then that this sculpture reflects in part its maritime history. This is no ordinary rock. The rock is an example of &#8216;windblown&#8217; sandstone and has no inclusions such as shell fragments.</p>
<p><strong>Ambient light</strong></p>
<p>It surprised me to see how much the garden setting influenced the mood of each of my sculptures. The sun provides subtly changing light conditions and the work seemed to &#8216;come alive&#8217;. This is quite a change from the static lighting in many gallery spaces.</p>
<p><strong>Sleepover</strong></p>
<p>I took advantage of a nights accommodation in a local deconsecrated church made of granite in the early 1800s. A farmer bought the church and used it as a shearing shed for 60 years. It appears he traded the pews for his ewes! Luckily architects from Sydney have now remodelled the building honouring its past history while creating up market accommodation. What a treat</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/willowtree-sculpture-garden/">Willowtree sculpture garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/willowtree-sculpture-garden/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">758</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>River Dreaming &#8211; (of becoming a lake)</title>
		<link>/river-dreaming-becoming-lake/</link>
		<comments>/river-dreaming-becoming-lake/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 08:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeffrey Frith]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=749</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>River dreaming &#8211; (dreaming of becoming a lake). This work was recently sold by a gallery in Bowral. My inspiration for this worked came from my desire to connect with the environment and the spectacular landscape. When carving stone I use power tools, angle grinders and hammer drills as well as the traditional mallets and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/river-dreaming-becoming-lake/">River Dreaming &#8211; (of becoming a lake)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>River dreaming &#8211; (dreaming of becoming a lake).</p>
<p>This work was recently sold by a gallery in Bowral. My inspiration for this worked came from my desire to connect with the environment and the spectacular landscape. When carving stone I use power tools, angle grinders and hammer drills as well as the traditional mallets and chisels. Sculpting is often a noisy, dusty and dangerous operation. It is not surprising that I spent many hours each work day on my own. I worked on this large sandstone block for many months while located on a cleared piece of bushland opposite Lake George, not far from Bungendore, NSW. The birds and a couple of dogs from the neighbouring property hung about and I was glad of the company.</p>
<p>Lake George</p>
<p>The last time Lake George was full was in 1998. The river disappeared underground and I think is due to reappear after approximately 20 years. The present cold windy and extremely wet Spring we are experiencing may indicate the waters of Lake George will reappear. I know the dry lake bed has sheep and cattle and the occasional lama. grazing upon its vegetation. Some areas are fenced off into grazing paddocks. These fences become submerged when the lake reforms and present an unseen hazard for those venturing onto the lake in boats.</p>
<p>Sculptural form</p>
<p>The form of the sculpture hints at the shape of the lake which is twice as long as it is wide. It takes about 4 hours to walk across the dry lake bed which gives you some idea of the scale. The dazzling blue sky dotted with white clouds arching overhead seems so vast. River dreaming is connected to this ancient landscape. The flowing abstract forms embody the energy and magic of this time and place.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/river-dreaming-becoming-lake/">River Dreaming &#8211; (of becoming a lake)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/river-dreaming-becoming-lake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">749</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban insights</title>
		<link>/urban-insights/</link>
		<comments>/urban-insights/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 22:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=741</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>All in a day’s walk Ring the bells that still can ring. Forget your perfect offering. There is a crack in everything That is how the light gets in. Leonard Cohen</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/urban-insights/">Urban insights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/IMG_0661.jpeg" rel="attachment wp-att-732"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-732 aligncenter" title="img_0661-jpeg" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/IMG_0661.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>All in a day’s walk</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Ring the bells<br />
that still can ring.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Forget your perfect<br />
offering.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">There is a crack<br />
in everything</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">That is how<br />
the light gets in.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Leonard Cohen</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/IMG_0676.jpeg" rel="attachment wp-att-733"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-733" title="img_0676-jpeg" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/IMG_0676.jpeg" alt="" width="1024" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/urban-insights/">Urban insights</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/urban-insights/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">741</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finished and I am thrilled &#8211; BALANCE</title>
		<link>/finished-and-i-am-thrilled-balance/</link>
		<comments>/finished-and-i-am-thrilled-balance/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 04:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Culture and Art Symposium]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=432</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The work is now finished and on the base. I am thrilled that the work has gone well; hard yes, exhausting yes, worthwhile certainly! I have many more images to share but these ones I wanted to share with you all straight away. Some of these images were taken late in the afternoon some with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/finished-and-i-am-thrilled-balance/">Finished and I am thrilled &#8211; BALANCE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The work is now finished and on the base. I am thrilled that the work has gone well; hard yes, exhausting yes, worthwhile certainly!</p>
<table style="width: 100%;" border="0">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>
<div id="attachment_422" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image017.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-422" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image017-300x199.jpg" alt="Maquette carved in pink marble" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maquette carved in pink marble</p></div>
<div id="attachment_392" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image079.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-392" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image079-300x225.jpg" alt="The sculpture is signed and washed down" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The sculpture is signed and washed down</p></div>
<div id="attachment_407" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image083.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-407" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image083-300x225.jpg" alt="Korean sculptor Mr Song at his studio" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Korean sculptor Mr Song at his studio</p></div>
<p><div id="attachment_416" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image085.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-416" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/image085-300x225.jpg" alt="Mr IM on my left at the official presentation." width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mr IM on my left at the official presentation.</p></div></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I have many more images to share but these ones I wanted to share with you all straight away. Some of these images were taken late in the afternoon some with flash. I also wet the work so you can see what it will look like after a rain storm which gives a good contrast between the white granite and the black granite base.  Weather has been sunny with only one day of rain For the last few day the mornings have been cool and by 4 PM the wind has an icy chill about it. Lots of work but lots of fun.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/finished-and-i-am-thrilled-balance/">Finished and I am thrilled &#8211; BALANCE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/finished-and-i-am-thrilled-balance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">432</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.069 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2018-12-20 17:06:48 -->

<!-- Compression = gzip -->