<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>China &#8211; Jeffrey Frith</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/china/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Visual artist</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 11:58:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.12</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">117361521</site>	<item>
		<title>Where to from here</title>
		<link>/where-to-from-here/</link>
		<comments>/where-to-from-here/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 12:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The last days of our stay in Changchun were devoted to attending the 3rd International Sculpture Conference. This was a huge affair with over 300 delegates. The opening ceremony was held in a vast open square at the World Sculpture Park. There were speeches aplenty, a Ceramics exhibition to look at as well as a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/where-to-from-here/">Where to from here</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0739-web.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-239" title="Where to from here1" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0739-web.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /></a><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0-web.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-238" title="Where to from here" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0-web.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /></a><a href="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0845-web.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-240" title="Where to from here2" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/img_0845-web.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /></a>The last days of our stay in Changchun were devoted to attending the 3<sup>rd</sup> International Sculpture Conference. This was a huge affair with over 300 delegates. The opening ceremony was held in a vast open square at the World Sculpture Park. There were speeches aplenty, a Ceramics exhibition to look at as well as a collection of contemporary African art.</p>
<p>Presenters from many different countries presented papers on a diverse range of subjects including, The role of sculpture in urban public art and The impact of globalization on Culture. Roger McFarlane, Past President of The Sculptors Society in Australia presented an interesting topic, the Sculptor’s elite achievement and the public audience’s aesthetic standard. His presentation was well illustrated with visual images and engaged his mainly Chinese audience.</p>
<p>So with all the speeches openings and unveilings behind us the sculptors assembled in Changchun for the International Sculpture Symposium and the International Sculpture Conference have finally left. Some have moved on to another symposium in Penza , Russia, while others have returned home.</p>
<p>Other sculptors face the prospect of civil unrest in their countries. Tornadoes have reached havoc in the Islands in the Caribbean and there have been rioters in the streets of old London town.</p>
<p>A number of sculptors have jobs as teachers, while others will travel to Europe to meet collectors and check out the Gallery scene. Where sculptors have promised to deliver commissioned projects work is waiting to be completed back in their studios.</p>
<p>But one thing is sure, whatever we do from here on will be influenced by the 6 weeks we have spent in symposium held in Changchun. A symposium has been described as a conference or meeting for the discussion of some subject, especially an academic topic or social problem while in an historical sense a symposium is described as a drinking party with intellectual conversation, music, etc.</p>
<p>And we had it all in Changchun. The Committee arranged for us to visit a live theatre where excerpts from the Peking Opera were presented alongside an orchestra playing traditional Chinese instruments. There were beautiful dancers, acrobats and magicians as well to entertain us.</p>
<p>I count myself as one of a number of sculptors who felt that our artistic horizons had been broadened as a result of the interaction with artists from all over the world. What an amazing opportunity we have had to learn from each other, to share our experience our dreams and our skills. And what an opportunity to watch China as it develops at such a pace, undertaking such large building projects and paying attention to the arts along the way.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/where-to-from-here/">Where to from here</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/where-to-from-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">237</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Unveiling</title>
		<link>/the-unveiling/</link>
		<comments>/the-unveiling/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 04:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=231</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine the scene. The NE Changchun City Urban Wetland Park has been a work in progress only a few days before thousands of people gathered for the unveiling of the Great Stone bearing the name of all the sculptors who participated in the 12th International Sculpture Symposium. My name is 8th from the top although [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-unveiling/">The Unveiling</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-233" title="Unveiling" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Unveiling.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-233" title="Unveiling" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Unveiling1.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-233" title="Unveiling" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Unveiling2.jpg" alt="" width="262" height="350" />Imagine the scene. The NE Changchun City Urban Wetland Park has been a work in progress only a few days before thousands<br />
of people gathered for the unveiling of the Great Stone<br />
bearing the name of all the sculptors who participated in<br />
the 12th International Sculpture Symposium. My name is 8th<br />
from the top although it helps if you are 8 metres tall to<br />
be able to read it.</p>
<p>I had been asked by the Committee to prepare a speech on<br />
behalf of all the sculptors. I was on stage<br />
with loads of Governors,Leaders, dignitaries, special guests<br />
etc., yet I was the first to speak.</p>
<p>It went well and I even remembered to leave time after each<br />
sentence for the translator to do her work. Some of the<br />
sculptors came up to me after wards and congratulated me,<br />
but more importantly said they felt I was saying the things<br />
that they wanted to say, that I had represented their views.<br />
One guy even requested a copy of the speech!</p>
<p>There were many speeches, a brass band played strident<br />
music, there were fireworks, pigeons were let loose to fly<br />
through a barrage of gold tinsel while sculptors received<br />
Diplomas from officials.</p>
<p>Eventually attention turned to the 100 sculptures that adorn<br />
this amazing park. Many people enjoyed a tour of the Park<br />
from the comfort of electric open-sided mini-buses. The<br />
Sculpture Park is one of a number of scenic areas covering<br />
in<br />
total 9.7 square kilometres.</p>
<p>While more landscaping work needs to be done and the<br />
positioning of some sculptures need to be modified it is<br />
amazing what has been achieved over the time we sculptors<br />
have been in Changchun.</p>
<p>Where there was mud now there is<br />
grass, where there was water now there are bridges over<br />
water, where there were trees now there are magnificent<br />
rocks and flowers seeking attention along with sculptures in<br />
stone,metal and bronze.</p>
<p>The works to be cast in bronze are represented in the park<br />
by fibre-glass replicas of sculptures. These will be used in<br />
the casting process over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>Today has been a marvelous day for<br />
so many people connected with this project and the weather<br />
was perfect. I have included my speech here for interest&#8217;s<br />
sake.</p>
<p>&#8220;Governors, Distinguished guests, Fellow Sculptors and<br />
friends; good morning. I extend a warm welcome to you all on<br />
behalf of the sculptors assembled here today.<br />
This is a great day for all of those connected with the 12th<br />
International Sculpture Symposium in Changchun (High- Tech<br />
Development Zone) as it signifies the culmination of a great<br />
deal of hard work.</p>
<p>This Symposium is the largest Sculpture Symposium ever held<br />
with over 100 sculptors from 5 continents participating.<br />
We sculptors offer our sincere thanks to all those who have<br />
worked so hard to make this Symposium a success.<br />
It has been a joy to work with our enthusiastic<br />
interpreters. These students have promoted understanding<br />
amongst a diverse group of people from diverse cultural<br />
backgrounds.</p>
<p>We sculptors also appreciate the effort put in by those<br />
managing the work sites, the artisans and crane drivers<br />
whose work has been indispensable over the past 6 weeks.<br />
Their efforts have ensured our monumental sculptures in<br />
stone, bronze and metal could be completed on time .</p>
<p>I am sure I can speak on behalf of all the sculptors<br />
present when I say, thank you to the citizens of Changchun.<br />
The on-going support you give to beautifying your city with<br />
sculpture and sculpture parks will result in Changchun<br />
becoming known worldwide as the ‘Sculpture Capital of<br />
China’. &#8220;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-unveiling/">The Unveiling</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/the-unveiling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">231</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polishing</title>
		<link>/polishing/</link>
		<comments>/polishing/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>How many people does it take to polish 2 huge blocks of marble? A far as my sculpture Cloudstone is concerned it took 3 days starting with 2 people and ending up with 7. It seemed to me that the workers showed little regard for going through the grades from coarse to fine but somehow [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/polishing/">Polishing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-228" title="polishing.jpg" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/polishing.jpg.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-228" title="polishing2.jpg" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/polishing2.jpg.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-228" title="polishing3.jpg" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/polishing3.jpg.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="262" />How many people does it take to polish 2 huge blocks of marble? A far as my sculpture Cloudstone is concerned it took 3 days starting with 2 people and ending up with 7. It seemed to me that the workers showed little regard for going through the grades from coarse to fine but somehow it all seemed to work out OK.</p>
<p>The final polish was done wet. The accepted way of getting water onto diamond blades and pads or stone sculptures is to run a plastic tube from a bucket full of water placed on a wooden stand or on top of the sculpture and siphoning the water through. Simple but effective. The polished marble looks amazing with very rich warm colouring in the base  block shot through with blue/grey streaks. The top block however is not so dramatic and has muted yellows and pale orange as the predominant colours.</p>
<p>With a few exceptions all the sculptures are currently being assembled at the northern park site some 50 ks from Changchun. The site is still being developed so we sculptors are not sure what we will find when we are finally allowed to visit the site later this month.</p>
<p>Before we leave China most of the sculptors will attend the International Sculpture Conference here in Changchun. I believe there are 300 invited guests many of whom will present papers over the 2 days of the conference.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/polishing/">Polishing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/polishing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walk in the park</title>
		<link>/walk-in-the-park/</link>
		<comments>/walk-in-the-park/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=218</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The sculpture Cloudstone was uplifted about 5 this morning while I slept and will be assembled along with the other sculptures in stone, metal and fibre-glass in the northern park. The park has been developed over the past 18 months or so. The sculptors whose work will be cast in bronze have been busy painting [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/walk-in-the-park/">Walk in the park</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-219" title="walk-in-the-park" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/walk-in-the-park.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-219" title="walk-in-the-park" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/walk-in-the-park2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-219" title="walk-in-the-park" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/walk-in-the-park3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" />The sculpture Cloudstone was uplifted about 5 this morning while I slept and will be assembled along with the other sculptures in stone, metal and fibre-glass in the northern park. The park has been developed over the past 18 months or so. The sculptors whose work will be cast in bronze have been busy painting the fibre-glass casts of their work to simulate the patination they desire for the finished work. It may take up to 12 months for the works to be cast into bronze so the fibre glass replicas will be substituted in the first instance.</p>
<p>There have been some strange sights as the fibre-glass sculptures have been moved to various parts of the University. The Architecture and Civil Engineering university has over the past month provided a huge amount of space for the sculptors to do their work. No sight has been quite as strange as the 5 metre high Praying Monk created by a Greek artist which I spied roped in a horizontal position at the back of a truck. It reminded me of Gulliver and his adventures with the wee folk of Lilliput.</p>
<p>No artists are permitted to be present during the assembly stage as the organisers feel it is too dangerous for us. The real reason may well be that it would be an almost impossible task to satisfy the specific requirements of the 100 sculptors, each demanding the best possible location for their work, so best keep them at arms length.</p>
<p>A Polish sculptor and performance artist provided some light entertainment this afternoon which transformed the usually chaotic, dusty, noisy work site into a performance stage. Having frightened the life out of a gold fish he proceeded to ensnare people, bikes, sculptures and sundry other objects in what seemed like and endless ribbon of red cloth. Like a magician he produced what appeared to be bottles of Vodka (or was it water) and poured drinks as a reward for many of the appreciative crowd.</p>
<p>We left the work site mid-afternoon and spent some quality time in a nearby park; I chose to meditate by an extremely large lotus pond with the lotus in blossom and the light wind ruffling the lotus leaves. They do parks extremely well from what I have seen in this Provence. What they needed to complete the picture was a first class coffee shop! All in all it was an easy day today ending as it did with a walk in the park.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/walk-in-the-park/">Walk in the park</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/walk-in-the-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">218</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transporting</title>
		<link>/transporting/</link>
		<comments>/transporting/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=213</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today I had a visit from the guy who manages the work site. He informed me that in 2 days time my sculpture, along with others, will be transported to the grassy slopes of the northern sculpture park where it will be assembled. I can do some work on the stones at the new site [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/transporting/">Transporting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-214" title="Transporting" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Transporting.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-214" title="Transporting" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Transporting2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-214" title="Transporting" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Transporting3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" />Today I had a visit from the guy who manages the work site. He informed me that in 2 days time my sculpture, along with others, will be transported to the grassy slopes of the northern sculpture park where it will be assembled. I can do some work on the stones at the new site if I need to do so. In the meantime he has assigned 3 artisans to compete polishing the stones. The final polish will be done wet as this will bring out the beautiful colour of this extraordinary marble. The sculpture will have to withstand high summer temperatures and 6 months of winter snow and icy blast from the Gobi desert which can drop the temperature to -30 degrees.</p>
<p>The artisans and the crane driver and I decided it would be a good idea to test the lifting method that had been devised. It was a tense moment;the slings had finally been arranged utalising iron rods that had been positioned at 4 strategic lifting points on the top block of marble. Would the rods take the load, would the load be properly balanced, would they be able to position the top block accurately without a location pin in the base block? After a couple of false starts the lift got underway. All the questions were answered I am glad to say in positive way. I inspected the metal rods later and noted that 2 of the thick metal rods had bent somewhat under the load. That is something that will need attention before the final lift.</p>
<p>The more time I spend working on the stones the more I see needs to be done, to be fine tuned the work so that lines have a beginning and an end point, that curves flow and harmonious relationships are established between repeated elements. One of the young university students acting as an interpreter came up to me on the bus back to the hotel and said, &#8220;I like your work, it is profound, it is good&#8221;. Made my day.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/transporting/">Transporting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/transporting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">213</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rain interrupts play</title>
		<link>/rain-interrupts-play/</link>
		<comments>/rain-interrupts-play/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 00:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=207</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Changchun is green because it rains a lot, mostly at night.But today it rained very hard so we sculptors returned to our hotel mid afternoon. The rain did not result in flash flooding and the day ended with clear skies. The rain revealed the depth of colour in the red marble stone on which I [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/rain-interrupts-play/">Rain interrupts play</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-208" title="rain-interrupts-play" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/rain-interrupts-play.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-208" title="rain-interrupts-play" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/rain-interrupts-play2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-208" title="rain-interrupts-play" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/rain-interrupts-play3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" />Changchun is green because it rains a lot, mostly at night.But today it rained very hard so we sculptors returned to our hotel mid afternoon. The rain did not result in flash flooding and the day ended with clear skies.</p>
<p>The rain revealed the depth of colour in the red marble stone on which I have been luck enough to work. The marble dries quickly. If there are any cracks or faults they show up as the water in the cracks dries slowly. One of th two stones has a fault line which the artisans identified prior to working on the stone but it was not considered to be severe enough to reject the stone. Where necessary the stone<br />
has had to be repaired.</p>
<p>Currently I am working on the stones with the 5&#8243; diamond flush face diamond blade I brought with me from Australia As I can not find a 5&#8243; angle grinder I have resorted to using the blade on a 9&#8243; angle grinder with compatible RPM rating. It is OK but the machine is heavy and awkward to use doing shaping work. So I play with the shapes of the many lines carved into the stone and enjoy the work.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/rain-interrupts-play/">Rain interrupts play</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/rain-interrupts-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working the stone</title>
		<link>/working-the-stone/</link>
		<comments>/working-the-stone/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 23:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=204</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The artisans have spent the past 2 weeks working on the two massive blocks of red marble. Now it is my turn to examine the work, make corrections where necessary and finish the work. I relished the opportunity over he past few days of working on the stones with my angle grinder. I caused a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-the-stone/">Working the stone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-198" title="Working-the-stone" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Working-the-stone.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-198" title="Working-the-stone" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Working-the-stone2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-198" title="Working-the-stone" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Working-the-stone3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" />The artisans have spent the past 2 weeks working on the two massive blocks of red marble. Now it is my turn to examine the work, make corrections where necessary and finish the work. I relished the opportunity over he past few days of working on the stones with my angle grinder. I caused a bit of a stir by kitting myself out with all my personal protective gear. I even slipped on a light weight pair of overalls to protect me from all the fine marble dust.</p>
<p>But the artisans had another question for me. How is the second block to be lifted into its final position? Normally the guy with the mobile crane would attach straps underneath the stone and lower it into place. No straps can be used on the final lift because they would be trapped between the two blocks of marble. And the rounded shape of the top block is such that the straps may slide up and lose the load. What to do?</p>
<p>One  way would be to drill 4 holes in the top block and insert metal rods. The straps would then wrap around the metal rods and the lift could be undertaken safely. The drilling and lifting may put undue pressure on the stone. To avoid drilling an alternative would be to cut 2 shallow channels in the base of the top stone to accommodate the straps which could be removed after the lift was completed. This sounds a good idea but relies on the crane driver repositioning the top block on its side risking damage to the thinnest part of the block. On balance we decided to go with the drilling solution and filling in the holes left by the metal rods once the sculpture is in position.</p>
<p>Although the marble blocks I needed were over a week late in arriving at the work site, the work has progressed well. At any one time there would be up to 4 artisans working on the blocks. The artisans have already moved on to assist other sculptors complete their designs. I have great admiration for the team of artisans that worked on my sculpture; they have been instrument in helping me realise a dream I had when I created the first Cloudstone that it would look great if it were 3 metres high. In fact my son Alexander created an image of my sculpture 3 metres high using the magic of Photoshop. And so it has come to pass&#8230;well almost.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/working-the-stone/">Working the stone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/working-the-stone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">204</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Together again</title>
		<link>/together-again/</link>
		<comments>/together-again/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 23:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>My two blocks of marble are back together again. Many days ago the blocks were place one on top of the other so the overall form of the sculpture could be established. The blocks were then separated and carved while sitting on the ground, using angle grinders with diamond blade cutting discs, hammers and chisels. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/together-again/">Together again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-183" title="together" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/together.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-183" title="together" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/together3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-183" title="together" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/together2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" />My two blocks of marble are back together again. Many days ago the blocks were place one on top of the other so the overall form of the sculpture could be established. The blocks were then separated and carved while sitting on the ground, using angle grinders with diamond blade cutting discs, hammers and chisels.</p>
<p>The main task facing us now the blocks are in their final position is to ensure that the key points on each block line up accurately. Of course there needs to be some minor adjustments. The artisans will follow the lines I have marked on the blocks with black ink and the design will flow seamlessly across the two blocks.</p>
<p>It is quite exciting to see the the top block swung effortlessly into place on top of the lower block and nudged into place while suspended from a large mobile crane. The work site is not so densely filled as some of the stone sculptures have already been removed allowing space for some other sculptors to set up.</p>
<p>The designs range from a giant parrot to abstract standing stones, a giant screw, as well as an &#8216;endless&#8217; spiraling column of granite slabs, to &#8216;bells&#8217; made from solid granite! Metal sculptures are also well advanced some fabricated from steel or stainless steel in a variety of geometric or free flowing shapes. A recent addition to the metal work shop is a 3 metre diametre steel sphere recently arrived from a factory in Beijing. The sculptor has drawn an intricate design of interconnected figures on the surface of the spheres.</p>
<p>These shapes will be plasma cut turning this heavy metal object into an intriguing work filed with light. And many of the sculptors working inside an enormous hanger of a room have completed their works in clay. Plaster casts are then taken of each of the clay sculptures. Fibre-glass is used to create a full scale replica of the original clay work. The fibre-glass replicas will then be spray painted to resemble bronze using a range of colours and patinas chosen by each sculptor. So there is never a dull moment. Always so much activity, so much to see and discuss, so much to observe and learn.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/together-again/">Together again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/together-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hands off</title>
		<link>/hands-off/</link>
		<comments>/hands-off/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 23:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=175</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Given the scale of the blocks of stone we sculptors are dealing with the organisers of the Symposium enlisted the assistance of artisans with experience working with stone. I have been supplied with 2 large block of &#8216;red&#8217; marble (apparently not as hard as the white marble) and 2 assistants. The work undertaken was to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hands-off/">Hands off</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176" title="handsoff" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/handsoff.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176" title="handsoff" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/handsoff2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-176" title="handsoff" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/handsoff3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /></p>
<p>Given the scale of the blocks of stone we sculptors are dealing with the organisers of the Symposium enlisted the assistance of artisans with experience working with stone. I have been supplied with 2 large block of &#8216;red&#8217; marble (apparently not as hard as the white marble) and 2 assistants. The work undertaken was to smooth off the two faces of the blocks so that one could sit flush on top of the other. This is pains taking work particularly when done with hand held flush-face 9&#8243; diamond cutting blades. Work was slow and I requested more assistants. Over the past few days a team of 3 artisans have removed a vast amount of excess rock and resurfaced the smooth faces of the blocks to ensure the best possible fit.</p>
<p>My role at this stage is to direct the work rather than do it; in other words hands off. This situation will change as the stone takes on a shape closer to the form of the finished sculpture.</p>
<p>At present I am enjoying watching how each sculptors&#8217; work is progressing.Each day I become more familiar with the processes involved with making large sculptures in stone, metal and bronze. The energy at the work site is terrific. However,the air is often filled with stone dust and fumes generated by welding and fibre-glass resin used in mold making. It pays to wear a proper mask, glasses and ear-plugs to lessen the impact of this industrial environment.</p>
<p>Thea Tini from the World&#8217;s smallest Republic, San Marino Italy, has enlisted my help to develop and promote a Project aimed at building on past experience and the energy here in Changchun to sow the seeds for a State of Art world wide! We hope to present this Project as part of the up-coming International Sculpture Symposium to be held in Changchun in September.</p>
<p>Watch this space.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/hands-off/">Hands off</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/hands-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">175</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting it together</title>
		<link>/getting-it-together/</link>
		<comments>/getting-it-together/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 23:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/?p=189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s the day the 2 marble blocks came together albeit briefly so I could draw the overall shape of the sculpture. This is trickier than it seems as the stones are still rough with little hope of drawing a straight line. The artisans use an inked string which they pull taught over the stone face [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/getting-it-together/">Getting it together</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-190" title="Gettingtogether" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Gettingtogether.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-190" title="Gettingtogether" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Gettingtogether2.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-190" title="Gettingtogether" src="http://www.jeffreyfrith.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Gettingtogether3.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="263" /></p>
<p>Today&#8217;s the day the 2 marble blocks came together albeit briefly so I could draw the overall shape of the sculpture. This is trickier than it seems as the stones are still rough with little hope of drawing a straight line. The artisans use an inked string which they pull taught over the stone face and give it a twang leaving a black line which they can follow for cutting or as a grid line.</p>
<p>Frustrated at not being able to communicate adequately with the artisans despite the best efforts of my friend and translator Zhong, I resorted to making a clay model which resembled the two blocks stacked one on top of the other. I proceeded to slice into the clay model in the manner and sequence I considered the best way to reveal the form of the sculpture. By this time a small group had gathered to witness the goings on. &#8220;That is OK in clay but we have stone to cut and that is not the way we usually do it. First we create the form of the stone, then we shape it. Just draw the outline of the form at this stage.&#8221; Even doing that simple task proved to be difficult as the artisans refused to let me scramble on top of the stone as they indicated it was unsafe for me; so one of the artisans clambered up instead and together we created the much sort after line on the stone.</p>
<p>I am learning so much working with these people who also love working with stone; we just come at it from different angles. I engage with a new stone by working with it, chipping away, cutting drilling to assess the character of the material. I then &#8216;feel&#8217; my way into the work exploring a variety of sculptural possibilities until one feels right and I see it through until all aspects of the sculptural work are resolved. The artisans have a different agenda, to work the stone to achieve a specific result. The scale model I brought with me from Australia has been then most useful item in my kit bag.</p>
<p>The blocks have again been separated and the cutting an hammering continues at ground level. And the count-down has begun as the sculpture needs to be completed before the end of August.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/getting-it-together/">Getting it together</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Jeffrey Frith</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/getting-it-together/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">189</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.085 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2018-12-20 17:06:53 -->

<!-- Compression = gzip -->